[Music]
hello McLaren Ville wine
spectator Robert
Parker okay
anyway Luke Marquez welcome to Taiwan oh
that's right Lefty Lefty thank you
William welcome to Taiwan is this your
first time here it's my first time into
Taiwan oh wow actually we were shaking
with our left hand right but are you
really left-hander so I am not
left-handed um I'm obliged to for the
business point of view but uh but my mom
my dad my sister and seven of our
original 11 employees left-handed so
you're the only one with the right hand
I always say I identify as being
left-handed but I otherwise I am
right-handed okay good well anyway first
thing uh that catches my eyes you know
every time I see your label it's it
really intrigues me can I tell our
friends in Taiwan what are these labels
yeah so my mom uh was the real mind
behind all of our labels uh she wanted
to create really abstract fun exciting
wines when we first launched Molly
dooker back in 2006 nobody had really
moved into that world of creative labels
so um um she wanted to stand out from
the crowd so uh We've created four
different ranges including our Lefty
range talks about my parents how they
grew up met each other as kids we have
our family range which is named after my
sister and myself okay we have our love
range which is kind of the philosophy of
Molly duok and then our Flagship wi
which is pelv glove being our Lefty
range we got the violinists uh named
after Mom she was 8 years old she wanted
to play the violin you can't play the
violin left-handed otherwise you'd poke
the girl in the orchestra in the IR to
you oh yeah that's right you wouldn't
want to do that no okay so she was
forced to play right-handed so that's
why that one is named as it is okay
violinist we call it's a red drink is
white very full body big ball so full
body white so the white is called ver
Vell verdello yep 100% vello And can you
give us a little tip on so we make big
bold juicy wines emphasizing on color
flavor and fruit weight so but U vidello
is like a a honeysuckle Citrus apple bit
of a little bit of white peach a little
bit of like even maripan and alond uh
goes into a little bit of French oakk
just to get a bit of wood no Malo but
really creamy um very lovely one the
next one is the scooter so my dad used
to race big rubber tied scooters up to
uh 30 km as a kid the first time my mom
ever met my father is he raced past On A
Big World scooter you know I was like it
was love at first sight or at the same
time I'm like and you still married him
yeah it's true
love yeah because you know
scooter not a Ferrari yeah exactly
scooter uh is 100% Merlo um and all of
our red wines we always say there's 10
flavors that we go for and you can see
them in every single bottle but they
start off at cherry strawberry raspberry
Blackberry fresh Plum spice chocolate
mocha plum jam Licorice and tar but
again cherry strawberry raspberry
Blackberry fresh Plum spice chocolate
mocha plum jam licorish
T but that one it's uh for a Merlo Merlo
quite traditionally quite soft and very
approachable but the way that we make it
is Big B really juicy um so it it was
really expressive probably my everyday
Drinker it's the one that I love the
most to be consuming with anybody and
then the boxer um so this one is
probably our most iconic one but this
one was a little bit more of a tribute
actually so when we started Molly dooka
we started mollya with $17 in our bank
account and uh a gentleman called Mel
dick uh he was the fine wine division
manager of Southern glazes Wine and
Spirits in the US she was the first
person to sign us as to uh start
Distributing Molly dooka in the US one
of the biggest wine market in the world
and uh he was a boxer and if he was a
left-handed person and it was a tribute
to him to saying thank you for giving us
a shot and um now it's been probably one
of the most iconic Shas in the world wow
but also I can tell that the the the
gloves is two left he's got two
left-handed gloves so yeah so it's not
quite a story about my parents but it's
more of story about the person one of
the people that helped us get to where
we are today okay and then the ma again
named after my father he put himself
through college uh being a left-handed
uh matro a left-handed waiter at the
local restaurant and then he had a huge
passion for wine so went and studied
wine is that and that's where we met my
mom okay we have the matri D is what
great 100% cabin 100% cab you got that
beautiful cab uh structure um little bit
of perzine but then you put on your
palette it's just super fruit as the
next one to feet is after again after
both of my parents so my mom loves to
dance my dad can't dance so it's my dad
standing on my mom's toes two fe's
actually a fun wine because actually a
blend of all three of these Wines in one
bottle okay so it's actually 70% of the
boxer okay 15% of the matro 15% of the
scooter finished and then blended into
to a feet so it's actually all three of
those wies put into one BX does change
percentages from year to year so but
it's always predominant about 70 shiras
1515 cabill we call the Lefty series y
then the Family series which is named
after my sister and myself okay so uh
gigglepot named after Holly so she loved
to and still loves to laugh so it was
her nickname as a kid gigglepot is our
premium cabinet so it's the premium
version of the matro D okay so um a
single Vineyard comes only from one
little block called Rivers Lane I always
smell it and I literally get jalapenos
on the nose like it's super spicy but
then you put on it and there's just so
much fruit blueeye boy named after
myself so I had I still have piercing
blue eyes 100% again it's a step up from
boxing weight and this one I it smells
like blueberry vanilla cream or
blueberry muffins dominates by that blue
fruit which is cool cuz it's called BL
boy so can you what's the difference
between um this and this so this is
going up a teer level and something that
we call fruit weight it's the silky
sensation memory of fruit of how far
back it goes on your palette it's a just
a was way for us to grade the wines and
create consistency you know we don't
make every single wine every a year cuz
if it doesn't get to the Quality we
won't put it in and we will not sell it
so allows us to stay consistent a lot of
people talk about length you know like
how was the length or how was the finish
of the wine we talk about fruit weight
it's not how heavy the food is it's the
silky sens and this is very unique to
yeah so we come to an understanding of
how to measure it my mom really kind of
grasp that Carnival love our most
accolate wine and part of our love ser
series The Fruit weight goes above
another teer when we go to the love
series y yeah when you put them together
they make one big photo there's just
there's a lot of detail in this bottle
and then if you actually look so they're
cartoon characters but in here all the
characters become humans yeah so the
violinist becomes a human the two left
feet the become humans so these are all
cartoon then where they go into the
carnival caral love they all humanized
they become human it's amazing we always
say everybody in their life in their
business in their family is on an
enchanted path every day and we are in
our own Carnival LA mollya and we invite
everybody to come well you we can talk
about that now velv glove is our
Flagship one we do not make this every
year it is a very iconic bottle when you
actually feel this label it's actually a
velvet felt so the bag is made of pure
velvet okay when you open it for the
first time you can see that that velvet
that M lines up and then everything
lines up okay when we actually hand
polish every single bottle it's oh wow
it's very very pretty so that there's no
fingerprints no scratches no nothing and
then if you actually feel the label it's
a velvet felt label so again the
attention to detail is to the height we
mom designed this bottle to be like a
woman curvy and elegant I have found out
that there's about three points Molly
dooker is different from other people
yeah so Molly
um uh has always been about challenging
tradition yes we want to make amazing
wines that stand out from the crowd um
and uh so what what we've done to create
that is those three points of difference
so one is our Marcus Vineyard watering
program we don't do the traditional dry
grown dry farming we actually irrigate
our Vineyards in a very unique practice
to produce premium quality wines that
are juicy and high yield um our second
point of difference is our fruit weight
which we've touched on which is that
grading system but our third point of
difference in what we are most known for
is uh the Molly Dua Shake it's really
it's really cute yeah so we preserve our
wines with nitrogen to preserve the
wines at it uh the the color flavor
quality at its optimal level okay always
also to reduce the amount of sulfur that
we use in our Winery okay but um it's a
very unique way that we're the only
people do it so so actually you have to
I I I from my understanding you have to
shake it to get the nitrogen out yeah
exactly and and you use the nitrogen is
because so that you can use less sulfur
yeah that's one of the what's one of the
points but it's also to preserve the
wine at its optimal State okay well can
you show us mollya shake so we can let's
shake it with with all of our brand new
mollya Reds you need two glasses side by
side all right so you get your bottle of
mollya you open it you pour a little bit
of wine out into the first glass I'm
going to do some for both of us all
right so this is a non Shake one just
pour it okay so then you're going to
need a put the cat back on really
important part turn the bottle upside
down and what we're going to do is shake
it for about 5 to 10
seconds
ah and and when you turn the bottle up
you can actually see that foam layer and
those are all nitrogens right so it's
nitrogen and CO2 CO2 and if you open it
listen
okay yep it's just like cook like rice
krispy yeah rice kisp yeah yeah close it
again turn upside down and then shake it
one more time
so now the wine is ready to drink but
the reason why you get two glasses is
when you pour it in the second glass so
it doesn't change the
color but it changes the flavor so smell
and taste the one here okay this is the
non Shake one non Shake took a meal y'
got it
right okay that's very
good wow it's
good now this is the shaked shake
it wow so instantaneously the wine
becomes more a creamier oh my God
rounder and smoother it's a huge
difference and I can feel the fruit
weight mhm it goes all the way back it's
like you know it's really really
nice it's a huge difference every time I
get invited to go to an event I take a
bottle of wine because if the
conversation becomes d and I start
feeling under pressure I bring out your
bottle I do the Molly shake and I become
the life of the party all right Luke
this question would be a little
sensitive but I think that a lot of our
fans and people in Taiwan would really
like to know because it is on the news
every day before the relationship
between the China government and the
Australian government was not at its
best Stage so a lot of the Australian
wines they can't get get into China and
they're really dumped around the world
so what what do you think about this and
and does it affect you so first and
foremost yeah so as the whole world
knows the relationship between China and
Australia broke up in you know Co time
they put a tariff of 212% 212% yeah so
you know almost you know ridiculous that
people can't you know operate with um so
it has affected the Australian wine
industry massively there was a lot of
people that um you know had all of their
eggs in one basket about China
um for as a Molly Dua standpoint we've
actually never sold anyone to China so
not even a bottle so we sell to Hong
Kong so Hong Kong so that is a market
that we uh we work with a great
distributor there called royal or um but
otherwise mainland China is not a market
that we've ever moved into so even
though that what happened it it affected
friends it affected other um wineries
you know a lot of them were hurt some
people went out of business so it's it
was incredibly upsetting for a whole
industry but we as mollya we were never
affected directly because our biggest
Market is us and it always has been even
when the GFC happened we stayed in the
US and we never left and we took the low
profitability but now it's flipped the
other way and now that China dropped
everyone's trying to go back into the us
but we're already there we had
incredible partners are all already
around the world and we sold out every
year so we didn't we didn't have extra
production to sell to them we sold to
Taiwan we sold to Hong Kong we sold to
Korea we sold to Indonesia Thailand us
Europe um and we were comfortable so so
yes as as you said it was detrimental to
the Australian wine industry but for a
mollya standpoint and for us in Taiwan
we're growing what we're doing in Taiwan
because we want we we've got we're
increasing our production and the
opportunity but it's not about
displacing what we lost in China we
never actually dealt with China wow
that's that's really good I really um I
really like you Luke I think he's very
genuine you're very genuine and you
speak of the truth thank you for coming
I need to shake your hands with your
left thank you very much it's been
awesome yeah it was really cool
well
Cheers Cheers L thanks for coming thank
you cheers
cheers